In the previous videos, we put
在前面的视频中
together almost all
我们总结了
the pieces you need in order
所有
to implement and train in your network.
需要在网络中实施和训练的部分
There's just one last idea I
现在是最后一个
need to share with you, which
我需要分享给你们的想法
is the idea of random initialization.
这就是随机初始化的思想
When you're running an algorithm like
当你运行一个算法
gradient descent or also the
例如梯度下降算法
advanced optimization algorithms, we
或者是先进的优化算法时
need to pick some initial value for the parameters theta.
我们需要给变量θ一些初始值
So for the advanced optimization algorithm, you know,
所以对于那些先进的优化算法
it assumes that you will
假设
pass it some initial value
给变量θ
for the parameters theta.
传递一些初始值
Now let's consider gradient descent.
现在让我们考虑梯度下降
For that, you know, we also need to initialize theta to something.
同样 我们需要把θ初始化成一些值
And then we can slowly take steps
接下来使用梯度下降方法
go downhill, using graded descent,
慢慢地执行这些步骤使其下降
to go downhill to minimize the function J of theta.
使θ的函数J下降到最小
So what do we set the initial value of theta to?
那么θ的初始值该设置为多少呢？
Is it possible to set
是否可以
the initial value of theta
将θ的初始值设为
to the vector of all zeroes.
全部是0的向量
Whereas this worked okay when we were using logistic regression.
当使用逻辑回归
Initializing all of your
初始化所有变量为0
parameters to zero actually
这样做是否可行
does not work when you're trading a neural network.
实际上在训练神经网络时这样做是不可行的
Consider training the following neural network.
以训练这个神经网络为例
And let's say we initialized all of the parameters in the network to zero.
照之前所说将网络中的所有变量初始化为0
And if you do that then
如果是这样的话
what that means is that
具体来说就是
at the initialization this blue weight, that I'm covering blue
当初始化这条蓝色权重
is going to equal to that weight.
使这条被涂为蓝色的权重等于那条蓝色的权重
So, they're both zero.
他们都是0
And this weight that I'm covering
这条被涂上红色的权重
in in red, is equal to that weight.
同样等于
Which I'm covering it in red.
被涂上红色的这条权重
And also this weight, well
同样这个权重
which I'm covering it in green
这个被涂成绿色的权重也一样
is going to be equal to the value of that weight.
等于那条绿色的权重
And what that means is that both of your hidden units: a1 and a2
那样是否就意味着这两个隐藏单元a1 a2
are going to be computing the same function
以同一个输入函数
of your inputs.
计算
And thus, you end up with
这样
for everyone of your training your examples.
对每个例子进行训练
You end up with a(2)1 equals a(2)2.
最后a(2)1与a(2)2结果必然相等
and moreover because, I'm not
更多的原因
going to show this too much
我就不详细讲述了
detail, but because these out
而由于
going weights are the same you
这些权重相同
can also show that the
同样可以得出
delta values are also going to be the same.
这些δ值也相同
So concretely, you end up
具体地说
with delta 1 1,
δ(2)1=δ(2)2
delta 2 1, equals delta 2 2.
And if you work through the
同时
map further, what you can
从图中进一步可以得出
show is that the partial derivatives
这些变量的偏导数
with respect to your parameters will satisfy the following.
满足以下条件
That the partial derivative
成本函数的
of the cost
偏导数
function with respect to
求出的导数
writing out the derivatives respect to
代表了
these two blue weights neural network.
神经网络中两条蓝色的权重
You'll find that these two partial
可以注意到
derivatives are going to be equal to each other.
这两个偏导数互为相等
And so, what this means, is
这也就意味着
that even after say, one gradient descent update.
甚至可以说 一旦更新梯度下降方法
You're going to update, say this
第一个蓝色权重也会更新
first blue weight with, you know, learning rate times this.
等于学习率乘以这个式子
And you're going to update the second
第二条蓝色权重更新为
blue weight to a sum learning rate times this.
学习率乘上这个式子
But what this means is
但是 这就意味着
that even after one gradient
一旦更新梯度下降
descent update, those two
这两条
blue weights, those two blue
蓝色权重的值
color parameters will end
最后
up the same as each other.
将互为相等
So they'll be some non-zero
因此 即使权重现在不都为0
value now, but this value
但参数的值
will be equal to that value.
最后也互为相等
And similarly, even after one gradient descent update.
同样地 即使更新一个梯度下降
This value will equal to that value.
这条红色的权重也会等于这条红色的权重
There will be some non-zero values.
也许会有些非0的值
Just that the two red values will be equal to each other.
仅仅是两条红色的值会互为相等
And similarly the two green
同样两条绿色的权重
weights, they'll both change values
开始它们有不同的值
but they'll both end up the same value as each other.
最后这两个权重也会互为相等
So after each update, the parameters corresponding
所以每次更新后
to the inputs going to each
两个隐藏单元的输入参数
of the two hidden units identical.
相同
That's just saying that the two
这只是说
green weights must be sustained,
两条绿色的权重必须持续
the two red weights must be
两条红色的权重必须持续
sustained, the two blue weights
两条蓝色的权重
are still the same and what
仍然相同
that means is that even after
这就意味着
one iteration of say, gradient
即使重复的说
descent, you find that
梯度下降
your two hidden units are still
你们会发现两个隐藏单元
computing exactly the same function that the input.
仍然使用完全相同的输入函数计算
So you still have this a(1)2 equals a(2)2.
因此a(1)2仍然等于a(2)2
And so you're back to this case.
回到这个例子
And as keep running gradient descent.
保持梯度下降
The blue weights, the two blue weights will stay the same as each other.
这两条蓝色的权重仍然相同
The two red weights will stay the same as each other.
两条红色的权重 两条绿色的权重
The two green weights will stay the same as each other.
也是同样的情况
And what this means
这也就意味着
is that your neural network really
这个神经网络
can't compute very interesting functions.
的确不能计算非常有意思的功能
Imagine that you had
想象一下
not only two hidden
不止有两个隐藏单元
units but imagine
而是
that you had many many hidden units.
有很多很多的隐藏单元
Then what this is saying is that
这就是说
all of your hidden units are
所有的隐藏单元
computing the exact same
被完全相同的功能计算
feature, all of your hidden units are computing all of the exact same function of the input.
所有的隐藏单元被完全相同的输入函数计算
And this is a highly redundant representation.
这代表了高度冗余
Because that means that your
因为 这意味着
final logistic regression unit, you know, really only gets to see one feature.
最后的逻辑回归单元只会得到一个功能
Because all of these are the same
因为所有的逻辑回归单元都一样
and this prevents your neural network from learning something interesting.
这样阻止了神经网络学习一些有趣的事
In order to get around this
为了解决这个问题
problem, the way we initialize
神经网络变量
the parameters of a neural network
初始化的方式
therefore, is with random initialization.
采用随机初始化
Concretely, the problem we
具体地
saw on the previous slide
在上一张幻灯片中看到的
is sometimes called the problem
有时被我们称为对称权重的问题是
of symmetric weights, that is if the weights all being the same.
所有的权重相同
And so this random initialization
所以这种随机初始化
is how we perform symmetry breaking.
解决的是如何打破这种对称性
So what we do is we
所以 我们需要做的是
initialize each value of
对θ的每个值
theta to a random
进行初始化
number between minus epsilon and epsilon.
范围在负?到正?之间
So this is a notation to
这个符号意味着
mean numbers between minus epsilon and plus epsilon.
负?到正?之间
So my weights on my
因此
parameters are all going
变量的权重通常初始化为
to be randomly initialized between minus epsilon and plus epsilon.
负?到正?之间的任意一个数
The way I write code to do
我在octave里编写了这样的代码
this in octave, this I've said you know theta 1 to be equal to this.
我之前讲过的θ1等于这个等式
So this rand 10 by 11.
所以 这个10*11的矩阵
That's how you compute
该怎样计算
a random 10 by 11
一个任意的10*11维矩阵
dimensional matrix, and all
矩阵中的所有值
of the values are between 0 and 1.
都介于0到1之间
So these are going to
所以
be real numbers that take on
这些实数
any continuous values between 0 and 1.
取0到1之间的连续值
And so, if you take a
因此
number between 0 and
如果取0到1之间的一个数
1, multiply it by 2
和
times an epsilon, and
2ε相乘
minus an epsilon, then you
再减去ε
end up with a number that's
然后得到
between minus epsilon and plus epsilon.
一个在负ε到正ε间的数
And incidentally, this epsilon here
顺便说一句
has nothing to do
这个ε在这没有什么用处
with the epsilon that we were
通常在进行梯度检查中
using when we were doing gradient checking.
使用
So when we were doing numerical gradient checking,
因此在进行数字化梯度检查时
there we were adding some values of epsilon to theta.
会加一些ε值给θ
This is, you know, an unrelated value of epsilon.
这些值与ε不相关
Which is why I am denoting
这就是为什么我要在这里用ε表示
in it epsilon, just to distinguish
仅仅是为了区分
it from the value of epsilon we were using in gradient checking.
在梯度检查中使用的ε值
Absolutely, if you want to
当然
initialize theta 2
如果想要初始化θ2
to a random 1 by
为任意一个1乘11的矩阵
11 matrix, you can do so using this piece of code here.
可以使用这里的这段代码
So, to summarize, to
总结来说
train a neural network, what you
为了训练神经网络
should do is randomly initialize the
应该对权重进行随机初始化
weights to, you know, small
初始化为
values close to 0, between
负ε到正ε间
minus epsilon and plus epsilon,
接近于0的小数
say, and then implement
然后进行反向传播
back-propagation; do gradient checking;
执行梯度检查
and use either gradient
使用梯度下降
descent or one of the
或者
advanced optimization algorithms to try
使用先进的优化算法
to minimize J of theta
试着使J最小
as a function of the
作为变量θ的功能
parameters theta starting from just
从任意选择变量的初始值
randomly chosen initial value for the parameters.
开始
And by doing symmetry breaking, which is this process.
通过打破对称性这一进程
Hopefully, gradient descent or the
希望梯度下降或是
advanced optimization algorithms will be
先进的优化算法
able to find a good value of theta.
可以找到θ的最优值